<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="..\transforms\pp2html.xsl"?>
<PP xmlns="http://common-criteria.rhcloud.com/ns/cc" name="Redaction Tools">
  <PPReference title="PP Reference" id="ID003">
    <ReferenceTable>
      <PPTitle>Application Software Extended Package for Redaction Tools</PPTitle>
      <PPVersion>2.0</PPVersion>
      <PPAuthor>National Information Assurance Partnership</PPAuthor>
      <PPPubDate>2015-08-06</PPPubDate>
      <PPCertificationID>unassigned</PPCertificationID>
      <CCVersion>Version 3.1</CCVersion>
      <Keywords>redaction; software</Keywords>
      <entry>
        <name>Registration</name>
        <description>National Information Assurance Partnership</description>
      </entry>
    </ReferenceTable>
  </PPReference>
  <RevisionHistory role="draft">
    <entry>
      <version>v 1.0</version>
      <date>2014-05-14</date>
      <subject>Final Version 1.0 Released</subject>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <version>v 1.1</version>
      <date>2015-06-16</date>
      <subject>Interim Draft - Update as Extended Package of the Protection Profile for Application
        Software</subject>
    </entry>
  </RevisionHistory>
  <RevisionHistory role="release">
    <entry>
      <version>v 1.0</version>
      <date>2014-05-14</date>
      <subject>Final Version 1.0 Released</subject>
    </entry>
    <entry>
      <version>v 1.1</version>
      <date>2015-06-16</date>
      <subject>Update as Extended Package of the Protection Profile for Application
        Software</subject>
    </entry>
  </RevisionHistory>
  <chapter title="Introduction" id="int">
    <section title="Overview" id="ppoverview">The scope of this Extended Package (EP) is to describe
      the security functionality of Redaction tools in terms of <cite linkend="bibCC"/>. Redaction
      is the process of selectively removing and replacing information from a document or other
      logical container of data for release to an audience not intended to view that information.
      Redacted information is not limited to classified material; other examples include privacy
      data, proprietary information, trade secrets, and legal strategy. Instances of redaction
      include replacing classified text with a black box to release a document to an unclassified
      environment, replacing privacy-related data such as telephone numbers with all Xs to release a
      database to a contractor, converting a proprietary format document to Portable Document Format
      (PDF) to release a what-you-see-is-what-you-get (WYSIWYG) document. The risk from improper or
      incomplete redaction is the inadvertent disclosure of classified or sensitive data.<br/>
      
      <!--Redaction has become a more complex problem due to electronic file formats, including
      documents, spreadsheets, databases or others that act as a logical container for data. These
      formats include the visual content as well as hidden data such as document properties,
      comments, and executable content. Users cannot easily access or examine some of the hidden
      data making it a substantial avenue for inadvertent disclosure. Redaction tools are designed
      to assist the user with review and removal of both visible and hidden information.<br/> --> 
      
      <!--In the
      past, the typical redaction method for electronic documents was to print the document, black
      out the necessary information, then make a photocopy releasing a physical document. This paper
      method has the advantage of assurance but the disadvantage of loss of usability. The physical
      printed copy is exactly what is visible, a true WYSIWYG representation of the information. The
      photocopy could be scanned back into the computer for release as an electronic document, but
      the usability is greatly diminished. This method of redaction is no longer satisfactory in
      situations where the released document must retain the usability of the original source, or in
      situations where the object is not a document but a database table or other unprintable
      container.<br/> -->
      
      Redaction is not sanitization. In the sanitization process, information is
      removed with no indication that the sanitization process took place. In the redaction process,
      selected visible information is removed and replaced with something innocuous (e.g. black box
      or text) so that the reader knows redaction took place. This replacement is a critical part of
      the process not shared with sanitization.<br />
      
      <figure entity="images/workflow.jpg"
        title="Figure 1: One possible workflow of an electronic document through the redaction process."
        id="workflow"/> 
      
      Figure 1 shows the typical workflow of a document from source to destination
      and through the redaction process. Other workflows are possible. <!--For example, decryption and
      re-encryption of data may be performed by the redaction tool without the data ever being saved
      as an intermediate file. Again, the host system is assumed to be secured to the level
      necessary for the decrypted data. -->Software vendors have the flexibility to devise their own
      workflow solutions for their target consumer. However, in any workflow, this protection
      profile applies only to the part of the workflow that is performed by the redaction tool and
      only to the redaction functionality in that tool. Other functionality in the redaction tool,
      other tools used in the workflow, the organization's redaction policy as well as security
      requirements and security policies that apply to other parts of the workflow are beyond the
      scope of this protection profile. <br/>
      <!--The original source of the document can be either internal
      or external to the system which hosts the redaction tool. If the source is external, the
      document will first go through the system’s security policy for importing documents, e.g.
      virus scanning. A document from an internal source was either created on the system or has
      already gone through security scans. When a document enters the redaction process, it should
      have already been checked for malicious executable content.<br/> 
      
      During the pre-release
      process, the user or another authority in the workflow determines what to redact using the
      organization’s information policies or declassification guidelines. The authority makes a
      determination about the release of images, audio, video or other complex objects that are in
      the document that may require other pre-processing before release. For example, the document
      will be examined for potential steganography attacks or a decision will be made to redact
      those portions that may contain such issues. For encrypted or password-protected files, the
      user will remove passwords and decrypt files during this phase, which assumes the host system
      is secured to a level appropriate to contain the decrypted data.<br/> -->
      
      <!--There are several
      different types of interactive redaction tools: stand-alone, plug-in, or multi-purpose. A
      stand-alone tool is self-contained and performs only redaction-related functions. A plug-in
      performs redaction-related functions as part of another application when installed in that
      application. A multi-purpose tool includes other functionality along with built-in redaction
      functions, such as a word processor that includes built-in redaction functionality or a
      redaction tool that also performs encryption and digital signature functions. This protection
      profile applies to the redaction functionality in all of these types of interactive tools.
      <br/> -->
      
      <!--During the redaction process, the user will manually mark visible data or select hidden
      data. The redaction tool will remove this data from the document in such a way that reverse
      engineering the document will not allow recovery of the redacted data. The organization should
      have a redaction policy that specifies which features of the redaction tool to use, such as
      whether to remove all hidden data automatically or to review and select elements individually,
      whether to replace redacted text with other text or with solid blocks of color, what color to
      use, etc. While this policy is part of the redaction process, it is separate from the
      redaction tool.<br/> 
      
      The organization will apply review and final approval policies during the
      review and release process. There may also be post-processing requirements for the document
      such as inserting special metadata, adding passwords, document encryption or digital
      signature. The redaction tool may include the functionality to perform these post-processing
      requirements but they are not within the scope of the redaction functionality of the
      tool.<br/> 
      
      Once approved for release, the organization may have additional inspection and
      sanitization requirements that depend on the source and destination. For example, documents on
      a classified system may have to go through additional processing before being moved to an
      unclassified destination.<br/> -->
    </section>
    <section title="Terms" id="glossary">The following sections provide both Common Criteria and
      technology terms used in this Extended Package. <subsection title="Common Criteria Terms"
        id="ccterms">
        <glossary>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Common Criteria">CC</abbr></term>
            <description>Common Criteria for Information Technology Security
              Evaluation.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Common Evaluation Methodology">CEM</abbr></term>
            <description>Common Evaluation Methodology for Information Technology Security
              Evaluation.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Extended Package">EP</abbr></term>
            <description>An implementation-independent set of security requirements for a category
              of products, which extends those in a Protection Profile.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Protection Profile">PP</abbr></term>
            <description>An implementation-independent set of security requirements for a category
              of products.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Security Target">ST</abbr></term>
            <description>A set of implementation-dependent security requirements for a specific
              product.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</abbr></term>
            <description>The product under evaluation. In this case, application software and its
              supporting documentation.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="TOE Security Functionality">TSF</abbr></term>
            <description>The security functionality of the product under evaluation.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="TOE Summary Specification">TSS</abbr></term>
            <description>A description of how a <abbr linkend="TOE"/> satisfies the SFRs in a <abbr
                linkend="ST"/>. </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Security Functional Requirement">SFR</abbr></term>
            <description>A requirement for security enforcement by the <abbr linkend="TOE"/>.
            </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term><abbr title="Security Assurance Requirement">SAR</abbr></term>
            <description>A requirement to assure the security of the <abbr linkend="TOE"/>.
            </description>
          </entry>
        </glossary>
      </subsection>
      <subsection title="Technology Terms" id="techterms">
        <glossary>
          <entry>
            <term>Visible contents</term>
            <description>The visible contents of the file; the visual representation of text, images
              and complex objects.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Obscured visible data</term>
            <description>Content that could be visible but is obscured in some way such as content
              that runs off an edge of the container, text in a black font on black background (or
              any color of font on a similar color background), very small fonts, cropped or clipped
              graphics or images, hidden layers, portions of an embedded object (e.g. Microsoft OLE)
              that are outside the view container.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Static data or metadata</term>
            <description>File properties such as author or creation date, stored form field data,
              undo cache or any data kept to revert to a prior version of an element or the document
              itself, incremental updates, collaboration data such as comments, tracked changes,
              workflow data, embedded search indexes, bookmarks, document info added by 3rd-party
              apps, accessibility data such as alternate text, etc.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Structural data</term>
            <description>Data that is part of the file format structure, such as a file header or
              fonts, and is necessary to interpret the file properly for display or
              print.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Functional data</term>
            <description>Forms, scripts, link Uniform Resource Locators (URLs), workflow data,
              action buttons, formulas in a spreadsheet, macros or any type of executable
              content.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Remnant data</term>
            <description>Artifacts of the original application or source file format such as remnant
              or unreferenced data from fast saves, unreferenced or unused elements, malformed
              elements that cannot be fixed, garbage data in the file structure.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Images</term>
            <description>The actual image data stored in the file as opposed to what is visible; the
              visible image can be cropped or resized but the full image could still be retained in
              the file format and may or may not match the visible image; some image formats can
              have their own metadata, such as Joint Photographic Experts Group (JPG) and Tagged
              Image File Format (TIFF).</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Complex Objects</term>
            <description>Objects that may have their own static or functional metadata and may
              differ between the stored and visible form, such as images, attachments, Microsoft OLE
              objects, Microsoft ActiveX controls, and temporal objects.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Temporal Objects</term>
            <description>A particular type of complex object whose representation extends through a
              time interval, such as video, audio, flash animation, slide shows, etc. References to
              “complex objects” in the requirements section of this paper include temporal
              objects.</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Metadata of objects or embedded objects</term>
            <description>Such as EXIF data of images; images themselves can contain other images and
              their own metadata</description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Attachments</term>
            <description>An electronic document or data file that is part of the main file but is
              logically distinct and separable from the main electronic document.</description>
          </entry>
        </glossary>
      </subsection>
      <subsection title="Other Terminology" id="otherterminology"> The following concepts are used
        in the assurance activities. <glossary>
          <entry>
            <term>Simplify (or simplified)</term>
            <description>Replace a complex object or element with a single layer element that does
              not contain hidden or obscured data. The original representation of the object and all
              of the original hidden data must be removed from the document and the visible space
              must be replaced with the simplified element. For example, a document could contain an
              embedded spreadsheet on a page where only a small portion of the spreadsheet is
              visible within the view container on the page while content in the rest of the
              spreadsheet is in the document but hidden from the viewer. To simplify such an object,
              the <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> could create a single layer image
              (with no metadata of its own) from just the portion of the spreadsheet that is
              visible, place that image on the page and remove the embedded spreadsheet. This is
              just one solution. The intent of simplifying an object is to remove something complex
              that could contain hidden data and replace it with something simple that does not
              contain hidden data. </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Examine a test file or document</term>
            <description>The evaluator uses a hex editor or similar tool to view the raw binary (or
              hex) data of the file and the format structure. This allows the evaluator to view the
              contents of the file directly rather than through the <span
                title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span>’s interpretation of those contents. The
              examination can include the use of tools to extract, decode or decompress certain
              types of elements from the format, such as text or images. Care must be taken so that
              the extraction process does not change the element’s size, resolution, or content. The
              Technical Community will identify appropriate tools. </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Apply the TOE</term>
            <description>Follow the multi-step process where the user selects or marks areas or
              items in a document for redaction and then instructs the TOE to redact the marked
              areas and hidden information from the file. </description>
          </entry>
          <entry>
            <term>Test files</term>
            <description>To test the <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span>, the evaluator
              will have to use test documents that have content expected to produce a certain
              result. The evaluator will apply the redaction tool to the test files and examine the
              output to determine if it is as expected. The same test documents can be used for each
                <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> that produces the same format as those
              test documents. For example, a set of PDF test files can be used for all PDF redaction
              tools. Test files will usually contain only one testable item at a time to make it
              easier to identify that item in the structure of the document, but some test files
              should contain multiple testable items. The Technical Community will create a set of
              test files for the assurance activities for the most common formats. </description>
          </entry>
        </glossary>
      </subsection>
    </section>

    <section title="Compliant Targets of Evaluation" id="TOEdescription">The Target of Evaluation
      (TOE) in this <abbr linkend="EP"/> is a redaction application running on a desktop or mobile
      operating system. <br/>This <abbr linkend="EP"/> describes the extended security functionality
      of a redaction tool in terms of <cite linkend="bibCC"/>. As an extension of the App PP, it is
      expected that the content of this <abbr linkend="EP"/> will be appropriately combined with the
      App PP to include selection-based requirements in accordance with the selections and/or
      assignments made, and any optional and/or objective components to include: FCS_CKM.2.1,
      FCS_COP.1.1(*), FCS_RBG_EXT.2.*, FCS_TLSC_EXT.1.*, FIA_X509_EXT.1.*, FIA_X509_EXT.2.*. <br/>An
      ST must identify the applicable version of the App PP and this <abbr linkend="EP"/> in its
      conformance claims. <br/>This <span title="Extended Package">EP</span> is limited to the
      redaction of electronic documents defined in standards such as the series International
      Organization for Standards (ISO)/International Electrotechnical Commission (IEC)-29500 (Office
      OpeneXtensible Markup Language (XML), e.g. Microsoft Word, PowerPoint, and Excel documents)
      and ISO/IEC-32000 (PDF), or the definitive standard for a format. Mail guards, filters, and
      batch redaction tools are beyond the scope of this <span title="Extended Package"
      >EP</span>.<br/> Requirements that apply to features such as administrative control over
      particular redaction settings, multi-person review prior to release, etc., are outside the
      scope of this <span title="Extended Package">EP</span>. The <span title="Target of Evaluation"
        > TOE</span> may have those features but is not required to have them and their use and
      enforcement is governed by the organization’s redaction policy.<br/> This <span
        title="Extended Package">EP</span> covers the software functionality of the redaction
      process; it does not include requirements for how users should decide what to redact or other
      policy issues. Analysis of documents for covert data transfer is part of the decision-making
      process for what to redact and so occurs prior to the redaction itself. The requirements in
      this document are independent of requirements levied on document release by statute or the
      judiciary.<br/> Data execution risks inherent in some file formats are beyond the scope of
      this <span title="Extended Package">EP</span>. This <span title="Extended Package">EP</span>
      assumes that scanning for such risks occurs prior to the document entering the redaction
      functionality of the <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span>.<br/> Documents to be
      redacted may contain objects that are vulnerable to steganography, such as images or video.
      Functional data such as scripts can contain strings or images that may not be accessible to
      the redaction tool. Analysis of such objects for attacks or covert data transfer will occur
      outside of the redaction process. An organization’s security policy will determine whether
      such objects are released or redacted in their entirety. </section>

    <section title="Use Cases" id="usecases">Redaction Tools perform tasks associated primarily with
      the following use case. <usecases>
        <usecase title="Content Redaction">
          <description>Redaction Tools are used for the redaction of user selected content from a
            document. </description>
        </usecase>
      </usecases>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter title="Conformance Claims" id="conf">
    <cclaims>
      <cclaim id="Conformance Statement">
        <description> The Protection Profile for Application Software (<cite linkend="bibAppPP"/>)
          defines the baseline Security Functional Requirements (SFRs) and Security Assurance
          Requirements (SARs) for application software products. This <abbr linkend="EP"/> serves to
          extend the App PP baseline with additional SFRs and associated Assurance Activities
          specific to redaction tools. Assurance Activities are the actions that the evaluator
          performs in order to determine an email client's compliance to the SFRs.<br/> This <abbr
            linkend="EP"/> conforms to Common Criteria <cite linkend="bibCC"/> for Information
          Technology Security Evaluation, Version 3.1, Revision 4. It is CC Part 2 extended and CC
          Part 3 conformant. In order to be conformant to this <abbr linkend="EP"/>, the <abbr
            linkend="ST"/> must include all components in this <abbr linkend="EP"/> and the
          associated App PP that are: <ul><li>unconditional (which are always required)</li>
            <li>selection-based (which are required when certain selections are chosen in the
              unconditional requirements)</li>
          </ul> and may include optional and/or objective components that are desirable but not
          required for conformance. <br/> In accordance with CC Part 1, dependencies are not
          included when they are addressed by other SFRs. The assurance activities provide adequate
          proof that any dependencies are also satisfied. </description>
      </cclaim>
    </cclaims>
  </chapter>

  <chapter title="Security Problem Description" id="spd"> The security problem is described in terms
    of the threats that the redaction tool is expected to address, assumptions about the operational
    environment, and any organizational security policies that it is expected to enforce. <br/> This
    Extended Package does not repeat the threats, assumptions, and organizational security policies
    identified in the <i>Protection Profile for Application Software</i> (App PP), though they all
    apply given the conformance and hence dependence of this EP on it. Together the threats,
    assumptions and organizational security policies of the App PP and those defined in this EP
    describe those addressed by a redaction tool as the Target of Evaluation. <br/>
    <section title="Threats" id="threattable">The following threats are specific to redaction tools,
      and represent an addition to those identified in the App PP. <threats>
        <threat id="T.CLUES_TO_ORIGINAL_DATA">
          <description>Text or graphics placed in the redacted area by the <span title="Target 
            of Evaluation">TOE</span> may contain clues to the nature of the original 
            redacted information.</description>
        </threat>
        <threat id="T.UNREDACTED_DATA">
          <description>A failure of the redaction tool to remove user selected visable or 
            hidden data could reuslt in the inadvertant dissemination of information.
          </description>
        </threat>
      </threats>
    </section>
    <section title="Assumptions" id="assumptions">This section of the security problem definition
      shows the assumptions that are made on the operational environment in order to be able to
      provide security functionality. If the <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> is placed
      in an operational environment that does not meet these assumptions, the <span
        title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> may not be able to provide all of its security
      functionality. <assumptions>
        <assumption id="A.KNOWLEDGEABLE_USER">
          <description>The user is knowledgeable concerning document management and has appropriate
            training with the redaction tool. Part of this knowledge and training includes how to
            prepare a document for the redaction tool, e.g. resolve and turn off tracked changes
            prior to redaction, work with a copy of the document and preserve the original file,
            remove passwords and decrypt files, etc.</description>
        </assumption>
        <assumption id="A.INFORMATION_RELEASE_POLICY">
          <description>There is a redaction or information release policy in place for the
            organization which the user follows.</description>
        </assumption>
        <assumption id="A.PRESERVE_DOCUMENT_LAYOUT">
          <description>The <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> will preserve the layout of
            the document.</description>
        </assumption>
      </assumptions>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <chapter title="Security Objectives" id="obj"> This Extended Package adds SFRs to objectives
    identified in the App PP and describes an additional objective specific to this <abbr
      linkend="EP"/>. <SOs>
      <SO id="O.INSPECTION">
        <description>The <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> will analyze the file content
          for metadata and elements, to include any that are purposely hidden or not immediately
          visible to the naked eye. This metadata and elements includes, but is not limited to those
          that are obstructed from view such as shapes on top of text, hidden objects (manual direct
          formatting or programmatically hidden), and text that is positioned off the margins,
          and/or is located in header and footer sections of the file.</description>
        <component-refer ref="RED_DIN_EXT.1"/>
        <component-refer ref="RED_ID_EXT.1"/>
      </SO>
      <SO id="O.MANAGEMENT">
        <component-refer ref="RED_RVW_EXT.1"/>
      </SO>
      <SO id="O.QUALITY">
        <component-refer ref="VAL_REM_EXT.1"/> 
        <component-refer ref="RED_NND_EXT.1"/>
        <component-refer ref="FPT_FLS.1"/>
      </SO>
      <SO id="O.REDACTION">
        <description>The <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> will provide the capability
          to completely remove any data selected for redaction.</description>
        <component-refer ref="RED_SEL_EXT.1"/>
        <component-refer ref="RED_RPL_EXT.1"/>
        <component-refer ref="RED_REM_EXT.1"/>
        <component-refer ref="RED_LOC_EXT.1"/>
        <component-refer ref="RED_OBJ_EXT.1"/>
        <component-refer ref="RED_RIP_EXT.1"/>
      </SO>
      <SO id="O.REPORT">
        <description>The <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> will provide the capability
          to produce a report of all data redacted and any errors during redaction.</description>
        <component-refer ref="REP_GEN_EXT.1"/>
        <component-refer ref="REP_RVW_EXT.1"/>
        <component-refer ref="RED_ALR_EXT.1"/>
      </SO>
        
      <!--
        
      <SO id="O.Hidden Data">
        <description>The <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> will provide the capability
          to find and remove hidden data elements in the document. The <span
            title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> will include the capability to automatically
          remove certain hidden data elements that are unnecessary for the functionality, display or
          printing of the document.</description>
        <component-refer ref="RED_RIP_EXT.1.1"/>
        <component-refer ref="RED_ID_EXT.1.1"/>
        <component-refer ref="RED_ID_EXT.1.2"/>
        <component-refer ref="RED_ID_EXT.1.4"/>
      </SO>
      <SO id="O.Locate_and_Remove">
        <description>Complex file formats may store multiple instances of data in different
          locations within the file. The <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> must locate
          all instances of data to be redacted and completely remove this data from the
          file.</description>
        <component-refer ref="RED_LOC_EXT.1.1"/>
      </SO>
      <SO id="O.No_New_Hidden_Data">
        <description>The <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> may not add hidden data to
          the redacted file without informing the user. This hidden data may include metadata,
          document management system tracking information, or other process related
          information.</description>
        <component-refer ref="RED_NND_EXT.1.1"/>
      </SO>
     
      <SO id="O.Remove_References">
        <description>Complex file formats may contain multiple internal references to data to be
          redacted. The <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> will remove all such internal
          references.</description>
        <component-refer ref="RED_OBJ_EXT.1.1"/>
      </SO>
      <SO id="O.Replace">
        <description>During the redaction process the <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span>
          will place text or graphics in the area of the redacted information to signify data has
          been redacted. This newly placed information cannot convey any information which may offer
          clues as to the nature of the original redacted information.</description>
        <component-refer ref="RED_RPL_EXT.1.1"/>
      </SO>
      <SO id="O.Report ">
        <description>As users employ redaction tools to remove elements from documents or other
          types of logical containers, confirmation that the elements selected by the user and the
            <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> were removed is necessary. Report
          generation is one means of providing users with feedback about what was redacted. This
          capability allows the user to call up a report upon request.</description>
        <component-refer ref="REP_GEN_EXT.1.1"/>
      </SO>
      <SO id="O.Selected_Elements">
        <description>The <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> will provide the capability
          to select any type of document object in whole or in part for redaction.</description>
        <component-refer ref="RED_SEL_EXT.1.1"/>
        <component-refer ref="RED_RVW_EXT.1.1"/>
      </SO>
      <SO id="O.Validation">
        <description>The <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> will provide the capability
          to parse through the structure of the document and extraneous or unnecessary data without
          affecting the overall structure or functionality (e.g., display, print) of the document.
          The <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> will also provide the capability to
          parse different complex objects based on the format and simplify or remove those that it
          cannot interpret. In doing so, the <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> will
          produce a clean document for redaction without involving the user.</description>
        <component-refer ref="VAL_PAR_EXT.1.1"/>
      </SO>
      
      -->
    </SOs>
  </chapter>

  <chapter title="Security Requirements" id="req">This chapter describes the security requirements
    which have to be fulfilled by the redacion tool. Those requirements comprise functional
    components from Part 2 of <cite linkend="bibCC"/>. The following notations are used: <ul>
      <li>
        <b>Refinement</b> operation (denoted by <b>bold text</b>): is used to add details to a
        requirement, and thus further restricts a requirement.</li>
      <li>
        <b>Selection</b> (denoted by <i>italicized text</i>): is used to select one or more options
        provided by the [CC] in stating a requirement.</li>
      <li>
        <b>Assignment</b> operation (denoted by <i>italicized text</i>): is used to assign a
        specific value to an unspecified parameter, such as the length of a password. Showing the
        value in square brackets indicates assignment.</li>
      <li>
        <b>Iteration</b> operation: are identified with a number inside parentheses (e.g.
        "(1)")</li>
    </ul>
    <section title="Security Functional Requirements" id="SFR">The Security Functional Requirements
      included in this section are derived from Part 2 of the Common Criteria for Information
      Technology Security Evaluation, Version 3.1, Revision 4, with additional extended functional
      components. <subsection title="Report Generation and Review" id="RGR">
        <f-component id="REP_GEN_EXT.1" name="Report Generation" status="threshold"> Hierarchical
          to: No other components. <br/> Dependencies: None <f-element id="REP_GEN_EXT.1.1">
            <title>The <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> must be able to generate a
              report entry that contains metadata about each element that was redacted, including at
              least the following: the type of the element that was removed, the location if it was
              a visible element, and whether the element was selected by the user or removed
              automatically. </title>
            <note role="application">The report can be a configurable feature that is only generated
              on user request. Location can be a page number, a cell number for a spreadsheet, or
              some other indication that allows the user to easily locate the visible element. </note>
            <aactivity>The evaluator shall examine the <span title="TOE Summary Specification"
                >TSS</span> to ensure it describes the <span title="Target of Evaluation"
              >TOE</span>’s reporting feature and the metadata that is included for each report
              entry. The evaluator shall examine the operational guidance to ensure it contains
              instructions for the configuration of the reporting feature in accordance with this
              requirement. The evaluator shall create test files with specific elements to redact,
              apply the <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> to the test files, and observe
              that there is a report for each element expected to be redacted. This assurance
              activity can be done in conjunction with REP_RVW_EXT.1. </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        <f-component id="REP_RVW_EXT.1" name="Report Review" status="threshold"> Hierarchical to: No
          other components.<br/> Dependencies: REP_GEN.1 <f-element id="REP_RVW_EXT.1.1">
            <title>The <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> must allow the user to access a
              report of the data that was redacted.</title>
            <note role="application">This can be satisfied with a dialog box or other simple list of
              items that were redacted. The report can be a configurable feature that is only
              generated on user request.</note>
            <aactivity>The evaluator shall create test files with specific elements to redact, apply
              the <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> to the test files, and observe that
              there is a report entry for each element expected to be redacted.</aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
      </subsection>
      <subsection title="Validation Stage" id="VS">
        <f-component id="VAL_REM_EXT.1" name="Validation of Data" status="threshold"> Hierarchical
          to: No other components.<br/> Dependencies: None <f-element id="VAL_REM_EXT.1.1">
            <title>The <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> must remove unrecognized data,
              unexpected data, and extraneous structural data. </title>
            <note role="application"> Structural data is extraneous if it is unnecessary for the
              printing or display of the document contents, or unnecessary for the functionality of
              the document.<br/> Example - many formats include comments, e.g. PDF allows file
              format comments which are preceded by %. When these comments are unnecessary,
              unrelated to the printing or display of the content of the document, or provide no
              functionality whatsoever they must be removed.<br/> Example – some formats expect a
              header structure starting at the first byte of a file, but a tool may be able to
              interpret a file where the header starts at a later byte by ignoring the data that
              precedes the header structure. In this case, the preceding data must be removed since
              it is unexpected. </note>
            <aactivity>The evaluator shall create or acquire test files that contain unrecognized
              data, unexpected data, and extraneous structural data. The evaluator shall examine the
              files prior to redaction to identify the data. The evaluator shall apply the <span
                title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> but make no visible redactions and save the
              output files. The evaluator shall examine the output files, comparing it to the
              originals, to verify that the data has been removed.</aactivity>
          </f-element>
          <f-element id="VAL_REM_EXT.1.2">
            <title>The <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> must <selectables>
                <selectable>simplify</selectable>
                <selectable>remove</selectable>
              </selectables> any element which it cannot completely interpret. </title>
            <note role="application">For example, if the tool cannot recurse through a stream with
              embedded OLE objects, it must convert the stream to a single layer image with no
              metadata or remove it. If the redaction tool cannot interpret or process temporal
              objects, it must remove the temporal object and replace it with a simplified object or
              other placeholder. If a stream of data is compressed, encoded or encrypted and the
              redaction tool cannot uncompress, decode or decrypt the data, the tool must delete the
              stream.</note>
            <aactivity>The evaluator shall examine the <span title="TOE Summary Specification"
                >TSS</span> to ensure that it describes how the <span title="Target of Evaluation"
                >TOE</span> handles data that it cannot completely interpret. The evaluator shall
              create or acquire test files with data that the <span title="Target of Evaluation"
                >TOE</span> should not be able to completely interpret, apply the <span
                title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> and examine the output to verify that the
                <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> handled the data according to the
              requirement.</aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
      </subsection>
      <subsection title="Redaction Stage" id="RS">
        <f-component id="RED_SEL_EXT.1" name="Selected Redaction" status="threshold"> Hierarchical
          to: No other components.<br/> Dependencies: None <f-element id="RED_SEL_EXT.1.1 ">
            <title>The <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> must <selectables>
                <selectable>simplify</selectable>
                <selectable>remove</selectable>
              </selectables> any complex object, embedded object or graphic image which is selected
              for redaction. </title>
            <note role="application">The selection may be of either the whole element or only part
              of the element. If part of an element is selected, only that part must be simplified
              or removed.</note>
            <aactivity>The evaluator shall examine the <span title="TOE Summary Specification"
                >TSS</span> to ensure it describes in detail which complex objects can be simplified
              by the <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> and how they are simplified (e.g.
              whether the object or the whole page is converted to another format and what that
              format is). The <span title="TOE Summary Specification">TSS</span> shall also list
              those complex objects or images that cannot be simplified and will be removed. The
              evaluator shall create or acquire test documents that contain complex objects and
              examine the documents to identify where those objects are in the format. The evaluator
              shall then apply the <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> and examine the
              output to verify that the objects have been simplified or removed. The evaluator shall
              test all objects that can be simplified as well as all objects that should be removed
              according to the <span title="TOE Summary Specification">TSS</span>.<br/> The
              evaluator shall also create or acquire test documents with complex objects that are
              not documented in the <span title="TOE Summary Specification">TSS</span>, apply the
                <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span>, and verify that those objects are
              removed from the document. </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        <f-component id="RED_DIN_EXT.1" name="Deep Inspection" status="threshold"> Hierarchical to:
          No other components.<br/> Dependencies: None <f-element id="RED_DIN_EXT.1.1 ">
            <title>For each element of the file format that can contain its own metadata, other
              elements, or hidden data, the <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> must
                <selectables linebreak="yes">
                <selectable>recurse through the element chain and apply the <span
                    title="Protection Profile">PP</span> to each layer </selectable>
                <selectable>simplify the element</selectable>
                <selectable>redact the element</selectable>
              </selectables>. </title>
            <note role="application">For example, JPG images can contain metadata called exif data.
              Some image formats can contain the same image in another format, such as raw which can
              contain a complete jpg version of the image. A complex object can contain other
              complex objects (e.g. Microsoft OLE). The tool must apply the requirements to each
              layer of every element and identify hidden/metadata not just at the top layer of the
              document but in each element and in all layers within that element. If the <span
                title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> cannot recurse through the layers, it must
              simplify the element at the top level.</note>
            <aactivity>The evaluator shall examine the <span title="TOE Summary Specification"
                >TSS</span> to ensure it lists and describes the methods used to replace redacted
              elements that contain metadata, other elements, or hidden data. The evaluator shall
              ensure that the <span title="TOE Summary Specification">TSS</span>’ description
              complies with the requirement that each element is handled by either recursing through
              the element chain and applying the <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> to
              each layer, simplifying the element, or redacting the element. The evaluator shall
              create or acquire test files that contain elements that themselves contain other
              elements and hidden data. The evaluator shall examine the document to identify these
              elements in the structure, apply the <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span>,
              and examine the output to verify that the elements were handled properly via either
              redaction or simplification in accordance with the requirement.</aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        <f-component id="RED_RPL_EXT.1" name="Visible Space Replace" status="threshold">
          Hierarchical to: No other components.<br/> Dependencies: None <f-element
            id="RED_RPL_EXT.1.1 ">
            <title>The <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> must replace the visible space
              of redacted content in such a way that the visible space conveys no information about
              the previous contents.</title>
            <note role="application">A vendor may use several different methods to replace content,
              such as opaque blocks, text, whitespace or some other vendor-defined method. These
              methods must not convey information about the content being replaced. For example, if
              text is replaced with text, the replacement text must not indicate length of component
              words. Blocks of color used to replace parts of images must not show variations in
              intensity that could convey information about the image content.</note>
            <aactivity>The evaluator shall examine the <span title="TOE Summary Specification"
                >TSS</span> to ensure it lists and describes the content used to replace redacted
              elements. The evaluator shall ensure that the <span title="TOE Summary Specification"
                >TSS</span>’ description complies with the requirement to convey no information
              about the previous contents. The evaluator shall create or acquire a test file with an
              image, mark part of the image for redaction and apply the <span
                title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span>, and examine the image in the output to
              verify that the visual appearance does not provide any indication of the content that
              was redacted. If the <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> allows text content
              to be replaced with text, the evaluator shall create or acquire a test file with some
              text as content, apply the <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span>, and verify
              that the replacement text does not preserve word length or other identifying
              information that could allow recovery of the original content.</aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        <f-component id="RED_REM_EXT.1" name="Removal of Redacted Data" status="threshold">
          Hierarchical to: No other components.<br/> Dependencies: None <f-element
            id="RED_REM_EXT.1.1">
            <title>All data that is either selected by the user for redaction or identified by the
                <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> for redaction must be removed from the
              document.</title>
            <note role="application">Selected content must be removed, not obscured by encryption,
              encoding, conversion to a proprietary format, or any other method.</note>
            <aactivity>The evaluator shall examine the <span title="TOE Summary Specification"
                >TSS</span> to ensure it describes the removal of all data selected for redaction
              and verify that no encryption, encoding or proprietary process is used to obscure
              selected data. The evaluator shall ensure that the <span
                title="TOE Summary Specification">TSS</span>’ description complies with the
              requirement to remove all data selected by the user or identified by the <span
                title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> for redaction. The evaluator shall acquire
              or create test files that contain text, images and other elements. The evaluator shall
              examine the test files to locate the content in the format. The evaluator shall apply
              the <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span>, marking some of the content for
              redaction, and examine the output to verify that the marked content was removed and
              not obscured through encryption, encoding, or conversion to a proprietary
              format.</aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        <f-component id="RED_LOC_EXT.1" name="Redact Content from Every Location" status="threshold"
          > Hierarchical to: No other components.<br/> Dependencies: None <f-element
            id="RED_LOC_EXT.1.1">
            <title>The <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> must remove redacted content
              from every location in the file format where it is stored.</title>
            <aactivity>The evaluator shall create or acquire test files that contain content in
              multiple places and examine the files to locate the content. The evaluator shall apply
              the <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> and examine the output to verify
              that it has been removed from every location.</aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        <f-component id="RED_NND_EXT.1" name="No New Data Introduced by TOE" status="threshold">
          Hierarchical to: No other components.<br/> Dependencies: None <f-element
            id="RED_NND_EXT.1 .1">
            <title>The <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> itself must not introduce new
              hidden data that was not requested by the user without warning the user of the
              addition. </title>
            <note role="application">If the redaction process changes the format of an object, such
              as converting a complex object to an image, the conversion must not introduce new
              metadata.<br/> The <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> can modify or add
              structural data, including fonts, without alerting the user if the modification is
              necessary for the proper display or print of the file. </note>
            <aactivity>The evaluator shall examine the <span title="TOE Summary Specification"
                >TSS</span> to ensure it describes the actions taken by the <span
                title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> when removing, simplifying, or redacting an
              element. If structural data is added, the <span title="TOE Summary Specification"
                >TSS</span> shall specify what structural data is added and the purpose of the
              structural data. If non-structural hidden data is added, the <span
                title="TOE Summary Specification">TSS</span> shall detail the added hidden data and
              describe how the user is notified of the addition. The evaluator shall ensure that the
                <span title="TOE Summary Specification">TSS</span>’ description complies with the
              requirement to not introduce new hidden data, other than structural data, without
              warning the user. The evaluator shall create or acquire test files with complex
              objects or other elements and examine the files to locate those items in the
              structure. The examiner shall apply the <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span>
              and examine the output to verify that no new hidden/metadata was
              introduced.</aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        <f-component id="RED_OBJ_EXT.1" name="Removal of Objects and Corresponding References"
          status="threshold"> Hierarchical to: No other components.<br/> Dependencies: None
            <f-element id="RED_OBJ_EXT.1.1 ">
            <title>The <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> must remove all references and
              indicators in the structural data to objects that are completely redacted by the <span
                title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span>.</title>
            <note role="application">In some formats, there are references in the structural data to
              objects, such as a name dictionary in PDF. If an object in a PDF document, such as an
              image, is completely redacted (i.e. the user has selected the entire image to be
              redacted), then not only must the image data be removed, but references to it in a
              name dictionary as well as all structural references to the image must be removed. If
              only part of the object is selected for redaction, then the references necessarily
              remain in the file since the object remains in the file.</note>
            <aactivity>The evaluator shall examine the <span title="TOE Summary Specification"
                >TSS</span> to ensure its description of the removal of redacted objects includes
              the removal of all references and indicators to the redacted objects in conformance
              with the requirement. The evaluator shall create or acquire test files that contain
              objects and examine the files to locate these objects in the file format and all
              references to them in the structural data. The evaluator shall apply the <span
                title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> and select elements for complete redaction.
              The evaluator shall examine the output files to verify that the objects and all
              references to them have been redacted. </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        <f-component id="RED_RIP_EXT.1" name="Residual Information Removal" status="threshold">
          Hierarchical to: No other components.<br/> Dependencies: None <f-element
            id="RED_RIP_EXT.1.1 ">
            <title>The <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> must automatically remove all
              remnant data, undo buffers, tracked changes buffers, multiple versions of the same
              object, and any buffer or cache type container of data.</title>
            <note role="application">The user does not have to select this data for removal.</note>
            <aactivity>The evaluator shall examine the <span title="TOE Summary Specification"
                >TSS</span> to ensure it specifies the residual data and objects (e.g., remnant
              data, undo buffers, tracked changes buffers, multiple versions of the same object, and
              any buffer or cache type data container) that the <span title="Target of Evaluation"
                >TOE</span> will remove from files without any user interaction. The evaluator shall
              ensure that the <span title="TOE Summary Specification">TSS</span>’ description
              complies with the requirement to automatically remove all such data. The evaluator
              shall create or acquire test files that contain the types of data described in the
              requirement and examine the files to locate the data. The evaluator shall apply the
                <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> and not select anything for redaction,
              and examine the files to verify that this data has been removed
              automatically.</aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        <f-component id="FPT_FLS.1" name="Failure with Preservation of Secure State "
          status="threshold"> Hierarchical to: No other components.<br/> Dependencies: None
            <f-element id="FPT_FLS.1.1 ">
            <title>The <span title="TOE Security Functionality">TSF</span> shall preserve a secure
              state when the following types of failures occur: [assignment: any failure].</title>
            <note role="application">If the redaction functionality fails for any reason, the <span
                title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> must not produce a partially redacted
              file.</note>
            <aactivity>The evaluator shall examine the <span title="TOE Summary Specification"
                >TSS</span> to ensure it describes what actions the <span
                title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> performs upon any failure. The evaluator
              shall ensure that the <span title="TOE Summary Specification">TSS</span>’ description
              complies with the requirement to not produce a partially redacted file. The evaluator
              shall create or acquire test files that cause the <span title="Target of Evaluation"
                >TOE</span> to fail and observe that the <span title="Target of Evaluation"
                >TOE</span> fails and does not produce partially redacted files.</aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
      </subsection>
      <subsection title="User Experience" id="UE">User Experience <f-component id="RED_ID_EXT.1"
          name="Identification of Data" status="threshold"> Hierarchical to: No other
          components.<br/> Dependencies: None <f-element id="RED_ID_EXT.1.1">
            <title>The <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> must identify all hidden data
              in the document, except remnant data and undo or tracked change buffers, and allow the
              user to review and select each hidden data element individually for redaction.</title>
            <note role="application">Remnant data and undo or tracked change buffers are removed
              automatically according to RED_RIP_EXT.1. If the file or part of the file is
              encrypted, the <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> will have to reject the
              file or decrypt it so that the tool and the user can review the hidden data.</note>
            <aactivity>The evaluator shall examine the <span title="TOE Summary Specification"
                >TSS</span> to ensure it specifies the hidden data that it identifies and allows the
              user to select for redaction. The evaluator shall ensure that the <span
                title="TOE Summary Specification">TSS</span>’ description complies with the
              requirement for the <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> to identify all
              hidden data and allow the user to review and select each hidden data element for
              redaction. The evaluator shall create test documents with various types of hidden data
              apply the <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span>, and verify that it identifies
              each expected element and allows the user to select and redact each.</aactivity>
          </f-element>
          <f-element id="RED_ID_EXT.1.2">
            <title>The <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> must identify all obscured data
              and must <selectables linebreak="yes">
                <selectable>remove the obscured data automatically</selectable>
                <selectable>allow the user to redact the obscured data</selectable>
              </selectables>.</title>
            <note role="application">Obscured data is anything that could be visible but is obscured
              in some way, such as the cropped portion of an image or graphic. While the user sees
              only the portion of the graphic in the view container, the document contains the data
              in the cropped area. The tool must either remove the obscured data automatically or
              give the user the choice to remove or retain the obscured area.</note>
            <aactivity>The evaluator shall examine the <span title="TOE Summary Specification"
                >TSS</span> to ensure it describes how the <span title="Target of Evaluation"
                >TOE</span> handles all obscured data. The evaluator shall ensure that the <span
                title="TOE Summary Specification">TSS</span>’ description complies with the
              requirement that all obscured data is identified and either removed automatically or
              redacted by the user. The evaluator shall create test documents with various forms of
              obscured data, apply the <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span>, and verify
              that the tool identifies the obscured data and either removes the obscured data
              automatically or gives the user the choice to remove or retain the obscured
              data.</aactivity>
          </f-element>
          <f-element id="RED_ID_EXT.1.3">
            <title>The <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> must identify images where the
              visible representation is reduced in size or resolution from the representation stored
              in the file format and must <selectables linebreak="yes">
                <selectable>automatically replace the stored data with the visible
                  representation</selectable>
                <selectable>allow the user to replace the stored data with the visible
                  representation</selectable>
                <selectable>allow the user to leave the image unaltered</selectable>
              </selectables>. </title>
            <aactivity>The evaluator shall create a test document with an image that is stored in a
              larger size and resolution than the visible image and apply the <span
                title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> without selecting the image for redaction.
              The evaluator shall verify that the <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span>
              either <li>gives the user a choice to retain the image unaltered or replace the stored
                data with the visible data. For the choice to replace the image, the evaluator shall
                examine the output file to locate the image and verify its size and resolution, or
                extract the image with an appropriate tool for that format and compare the size and
                resolution of the extracted image to the visible image to determine if they
                match.</li>
              <li>resizes the stored image. To determine this, the evaluator shall examine the
                output file to locate the image and verify its size and resolution, or extract the
                image with an appropriate tool for that format and compare the size and resolution
                of the extracted image to the visible image to determine if they match.</li>
            </aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        <f-component id="RED_RVW_EXT.1" name="Element Review" status="threshold"> Hierarchical to:
          No other components.<br/> Dependencies: None <f-element id="RED_RVW_EXT.1.1">
            <title>The <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> must allow the user to review
              and select each element of visible data in whole or in part for redaction.</title>
            <note role="application">If the file or part of the file is encrypted, the <span
                title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> will have to reject the file or decrypt it
              so that the user can review the data.</note>
            <aactivity>The evaluator shall create test documents that contain images, text, and
              complex objects, apply the <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> and verify
              that each element is selectable for redaction in whole or in part.</aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
        <f-component id="RED_ALR_EXT.1" name="Redaction Failure Notification" status="threshold">
          Hierarchical to: No other components.<br/> Dependencies: None <f-element
            id="RED_ALR_EXT.1.1">
            <title>The <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> must make the user aware when
              redaction fails for any reason.</title>
            <aactivity>The evaluator shall examine the <span title="TOE Summary Specification"
                >TSS</span> to ensure it describes how the <span title="Target of Evaluation"
                >TOE</span> notifies the user when redaction fails. The evaluator shall ensure that
              the <span title="TOE Summary Specification">TSS</span>’ description complies with the
              requirement that the user is notified when redaction fails for any reason. The
              evaluator shall acquire or create test files that should fail the redaction, apply the
                <span title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> and verify that the <span
                title="Target of Evaluation">TOE</span> alerts the user that the redaction
              failed.</aactivity>
          </f-element>
        </f-component>
      </subsection>
    </section>
  </chapter>

  <appendix title="Optional Requirements" id="optional"> As indicated in <secref linkend="ccl"/>,
    the baseline requirements (those that must be performed by the <abbr linkend="TOE"/>) are
    contained in the body of this EP. Additionally, there are three other types of requirements
    specified in <appref linkend="optional"/>, <appref linkend="sel-based"/>, and <appref
      linkend="objective"/>. The first type (in this Appendix) are requirements that can be included
    in the <abbr linkend="ST"/>, but are not required in order for a TOE to claim conformance to
    this PP. The second type (in <appref linkend="sel-based"/>) are requirements based on selections
    in the body of the EP: if certain selections are made, then additional requirements in that
    appendix must be included. The third type (in <appref linkend="objective"/> are components that
    are not required in order to conform to this EP, but will be included in the baseline
    requirements in future versions of this EP, so adoption by vendors is encouraged. Note that the
    ST author is responsible for ensuring that requirements that may be associated with those in
      <appref linkend="optional"/>, <appref linkend="sel-based"/>, and <appref linkend="objective"/>
    but are not listed (e.g., FMT-type requirements) are also included in the ST. </appendix>

  <appendix title="Selection-Based Requirements" id="sel-based">As indicated in the introduction to
    this EP, the baseline requirements (those that must be performed by the browser or its
    underlying platform) are contained in the App PP and in the body of this EP. There are
    additional requirements based on selections from the App PP and/or in the body of the EP: if
    certain selections are made, then additional requirements below will need to be included. </appendix>

  <appendix title="Objective Requirements" id="objective"> This Annex includes requirements that
    specify security functionality which also addresses threats. The requirements are not currently
    mandated in the body of this EP as they describe security functionality not yet widely-available
    in commercial technology. However, these requirements may be included in the ST such that the
    TOE is still conformant to this EP, and it is expected that they be included as soon as
    possible. </appendix>

  <appendix id="biblio" title="References">
    <bibliography>
      <entry id="bibCC">
        <tag>CC</tag>
        <description>Common Criteria for Information Technology Security Evaluation - <ul>
            <li><a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART1V3.1R4.pdf">Part
                1: Introduction and General Model</a>, CCMB-2012-09-001, Version 3.1 Revision 4,
              September 2012.</li>
            <li><a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART2V3.1R4.pdf">Part
                2: Security Functional Components</a>, CCMB-2012-09-002, Version 3.1 Revision 4,
              September 2012.</li>
            <li><a href="http://www.commoncriteriaportal.org/files/ccfiles/CCPART3V3.1R4.pdf">Part
                3: Security Assurance Components</a>, CCMB-2012-09-003, Version 3.1 Revision 4,
              September 2012.</li>
          </ul></description>
      </entry>
      <entry id="bibAppPP">
        <tag>AppPP</tag>
        <description>
          <a href="https://www.niap-ccevs.org/pp/PP_APP_v1.1/">Protection Profile for Application
            Software</a>
        </description>
      </entry>
    </bibliography>
  </appendix>
  
</PP>
